Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and we've got another
lesson in our series
about small talk today.
That's right today we are at the office
again and we're going to be talking
very briefly about something a business
meeting that we're going to have soon.
That's right so let's check out our
dialogue we'll be back in a moment.
I'm a shell. Hi I was hoping to see you.
How have you been? How's the family?
Oh hello Mr. Campbell. I'm fine
and Jack's doing well. How are you?
I'm fine thanks. I got
you report this morning.
Thanks for that. Are you
joining the conference today?
Yes I'm leaving at 4 p.m.
Good well we can discuss this more than.
But I think the figures are looking
very good for this quarter. Yes me too.
I'm planning to discuss the
advertising budget at the conference.
I don't think we should
continue with the TV advertising.
No me neither. It's far too expensive. Well
let's discuss this more at the conference.
Maybe we can share a taxi there. Yes sure.
All right we're back so now let's take a
look at some vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Today
in language takeaway we
have a number of phrases
and words about business.
The first one we have is are
you joining the conference today?
That's right so we're
going to go to a conference
actually which is a little
bit different than a meeting.
That's right a meeting is something you
normally do with people at your own company.
But a conference is when people from many
different companies meet. That's right.
And also I think you don't really
have too much input at a conference.
You mostly listen to other people
speak about a topic or a subject.
That's right and I think these are normally
held in conference centers or hotels.
You have a nice lunch so they're
pretty big deals. That's right.
All right so it's it's more of a formal
business conference that we're going to.
And well they're actually
going to discuss different
aspects of the company as
well, especially the figures.
All right so in the context of business
the word figure actually means number.
Okay so we can say the sales
numbers for this year are a kind of figure.
That's right so we're talking about money
basically when we're talking about numbers.
That's right so when the
figures look good it means
that our income, our
revenue, this looks good.
That's right and when we
usually talk about income
or revenue we usually
have to separate it into time.
And here in the dialogue
we're talking about a quarter.
All right so quarter QU
quarter is a period of time
very common in business
that is a quarter of the year.
So three months. Three
months that's right.
January, February, March,
April, May, June and so on.
That's right so you have four
quarters and that's actually
what that's why you call it a
quarter because it's one fourth.
So we can say the figures for the
first quarter were very good but
unfortunately the figures for
the second quarter were very bad.
That's right and
actually another similar
way that you use
quarter is the 25 cent coin.
It's called a quarter because
it's a quarter of a dollar.
That's right and if you're
in America you know
that it has an eagle, a
bird on one side of it.
That's right.
All right so we are taking a look at the
figures for the quarter and they're saying
well it's not looking too good because we
need to talk about the advertising budget.
All right so this is something that you
you think is very important it's budget.
It's how much money you
have to spend on something
and in this case you're
spending it on advertising.
So this is ads that you make.
That's right so as you said a budget is the
amount of money that you have available
to spend on something and on this
occasion we're talking about advertising.
Now you can have a budget
for different things right.
You could have a marketing budget.
So the money you have for marketing.
You could have a personnel budget which is
the money you would set aside for people.
So how much you pay your employees.
Right so you can pretty much
mix up many different nouns
with budget even you can
have a budget for your home.
How much you spend at home.
That's right so many people
have this for their families.
They say this month I will spend
$100 on shopping and $200 on shoes.
So it's like a family
budget you would call it.
That's right.
Okay so that's all the words we
have for you on language takeaway.
Let's review everything quickly and we'll
be back in a bit with fluency builder.
I'm a shell.
Hi I was hoping to see you.
How have you been?
How's the family?
Oh hello Mr. Campbell.
I'm fine and Jack's doing well.
How are you?
I'm fine thanks.
I got you report this morning.
Thanks for that.
Are you joining the conference today?
Yes I'm leaving at 4 p.m.
Good well we can discuss this more than.
But I think the figures are
looking very good for this quarter.
Yes me too.
I'm planning to discuss the
advertising budget at the conference.
I don't think we should
continue with the TV advertising.
No me neither.
It's far too expensive.
Well let's discuss this
more at the conference.
Maybe we can share a taxi there?
Yes sure.
Alright in today's fluency
builder we have a number
of phrases you could use
in a small talk situation.
The first one is a question.
How's the family?
Now it's how apostrophe s the family right?
So how is the family would be
the extended way of saying it?
That's right but this
is a short way to say it.
It's very common and you normally say this
with people who are a little bit older.
People who have kids.
So I haven't seen you in a
long time Marco and I know
you have some kids and I
can say how's the family?
How's the family?
That's right.
And it's actually it may seem strange
the way that this sentence is made.
But it's very very much
similar to how are you.
You have how to be and you.
That's right and this is a
very polite way to say hi.
How are you?
How is your family?
How is the wife?
How's the wife?
And she said well you know what?
Everything is great.
I'm fine and Jack's I guess
that's her husband is doing well.
Jack is doing well.
So doing well thanks.
This means good.
Okay but you know when we say when we say
the answer to this question how are you?
I'm well.
That's that's the correct answer.
I'm good is not correct.
Right.
So if somebody says how are you you can
say I'm well or you can say I'm doing well.
That's a positive answer.
Things are going well.
You can say not so well that's not not
not not not good things are happening.
Very good and it's very important
to point out the difference
as Catherine said you don't
you don't you shouldn't.
Couldn't use good I'm
doing good or I'm good.
Yeah now it's incorrect
because good is an
adjective and we're
looking for an adverb here.
That's right.
Well that's right.
All right and to
finish things off Mr.
Campbell and Michelle we're
headed headed the same way.
So they decided to share a taxi.
That's right so to share
a taxi means two people
or three people will
pay for one taxi together.
So maybe Marco I see you on the street and
I know that you have to go to a conference.
I'm going to the same conference.
Let's share a taxi it will cost less.
That's right so you will share the
cost between all the people in the cab.
Now there's another
way of saying it as well
more common I think in
the in the United States.
That's right we say split
a taxi let's split a cab.
The split a cab now remember that
it's a taxi cab so sometimes people
just don't say taxi they say a cab
let's split a cab let's share a cab.
That's right cab taxi both are okay.
All right very good good stuff let's
listen to everything one last time.
I'm a shell hi I was hoping to see
you how have you been how's the
family oh hello Mr. Campbell I'm
fine and Jack's doing well how are you?
I'm fine thanks I got
your report this morning
thanks for that are you
joining the conference today.
Yes I'm leaving at 4 p.m.
Good well we can discuss
this more than but I think
the figures are looking
very good for this quarter.
Yes me too.
I'm planning to discuss the
advertising budget at the conference
I don't think we should
continue with the TV advertising.
Now me neither it's far too expensive.
Well let's discuss this more at the
conference maybe we can share a taxi there.
Yes sure.
All right so we're getting towards the end of our small talk
series as you can see we are taking a look at different quick
but very useful dialogues that you can have with someone a
small conversation whether about business family whatever.
That's right and in today's dialogue we heard two people who probably
know each other talking so sometimes you're with people who are
strangers you don't know what to say to them you can listen to our
other episodes on small talk for things to talk about with those people.
That's right and of course
if you have any questions
or comments you can
visit us at englishpod.com.
We hope to see you
all there until next time.
Bye bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]